Hello and welcome back.
In this lecture we will explore the confused deputy through a hands-on lab.
So here is the scenario.
Assume we are user A and we created an access token.
Using this access token, the user A can only and should only access entry ID that is
called 123 entry.
Our goal is to access an entry name called 456 entry which belongs to user B in another
organization.
If we go to jwt.io and decode the user A token, we can see in the permission, if we scroll
down a little bit in the payload, we can see the permissions are scoped to this organization
ID but also to entry ID which is 123 entry.
So we can read, write, delete, publish this specific entry ID.
And by the way you should have access to this access token in the resources of the previous
lecture.
Let's go back to the diagram and what we are going to do right now.
So we will use this access token to pass it to the back end to verify our assumption.
So we need to pass the token to the back end and ensure if we can get the entry ID 123
and then we try again with entry ID 456 and see what happens.
So let me bring the terminal and for simplicity I am going to just use care.
So we pass the access token in the authorization barrier header and then in the URL path
we pass the entry ID.
So if I hit enter we can see that using this access token, we can get the content of that
entry, we can get for example the body, the ID, the tags, title, updated that and then
also the entry ID.
Now let's see what's going to happen if I repeat the same command but instead of going
against entry ID 123 let me go back and then edit this to do 456.
Remember this is the one that we shouldn't have access to.
So I'm going to click enter and then we can see that we got forbidden and not permitted
error message.
Now at this point if you are doing a security assessment, you might try to tamper the JWT
token and change the scope and then maybe double check if the back end verifies the token
signature properly.
Now while this is a valid approach and nothing wrong with that but with the recent AI adoption
I want you to think differently if accessing the data is forbidden using a direct API access
check if that company or that target has AI service or MCP server.
It might give you a path to access the forbidden resources.
Remember in our case the goal is to access the 456 entry without tampering the JWT token
because the token is verified properly in the back end API.
Exploiting this is a little bit straightforward.
As I said before this is a business logic vulnerability and does not really require technical
exploit development.
So what we have to do is to log in as user A into the target MCP server and check if they
have related MCP tool that allows you to access content or entries.
Then try to pass an entry ID that you are not authorized to access.
And in this case we're going to try with entry ID 456.
So we go ahead back to our MCP server and then maybe go to the tools, let's list the tools
and then go to the get content and then pass 456 entry and then let's see what happens.
We can see that the MCP server it will get the content of that entry successfully.
So going back to the diagram and again just to resurface this the reason that this happened
in the first place it's because the MCP server has used its own access token with wide
permission to access the backend API instead of using the users own access token.
Again if we go to JWT.io but this time we decode the JWT access token that is assigned
for the MCP server and we scroll down a little bit in the payload we can see a wild
card permissions to access any entry and on any organization.
In the next lecture you will have an exercise to understand the other attack vector where
the MCP server might not have a wide permission access token but instead developers decided
to create an internal endpoint and then make the MCP server use that internal endpoint
to access any data that it wants.
I hope that this lecture has been informative for you and I will see you in the next one.
Thanks for watching.